来い 船井　決着をつけよう
Come on, Funai!
Let's finish this!
残り５分　星５つの大勝負
We're left with five minutes...
...to determine the winner
of those 5 stars.
４時間に渡る
限定ジャンケンの死闘
The 4-hour Restricted Rock Paper
Scissors match is ending soon.
決着の時 来る
The time has come.
すべてをかけた最後の勝負
Everything depends
on this final battle.
Iron Hammer
なんで負けると知っとって
戦わなあかんねん
I'll definitely lose,
so why should I waste my time?
しかも星５つの勝負やて？
アホか
And 5 stars for the wager?
Are you crazy?!
忘れたんかい Ｘのこと
Have you forgotten about X?
チョキ３枚 隠しとる奴は
必ずおる
Someone must be hiding
the 3 Scissors card.
電光掲示板の数字が
それを証明してくれとる
The scoreboard has
confirmed that.
Funai has a Rock card.
船井の持つカードはグー１枚
カイジはグー31枚と
Kaiji has 31 Rock, 33 Paper
and 2 Scissors cards.
パー33枚 チョキ２枚
チョキ３枚分の計算が合わない
They're short of Scissors cards.
つまり隠し持っているＸがいる
So, X is definitely hiding it.
なのに何でおどれと わざわざ
戦わなあかんのや
Why should I play with you then?
ボケが！ひっこんどれ
You creep, get lost!
カイジさん
Kaiji...
誰や？もう ええやろ
もう時間切れや
Who is it?
That's enough already!
Time is running out.
There's no time for bargains.
駆け引き 打っとる時やない
出て来い Ｘ！
Show yourself, X!
どいつや どいつ！
Stop hiding! Come out!
ま おどれが持っとるのは 戦えば
負けると分かっとるチョキやから
We all know that X's Scissors
will fail him if he fights.
そう たやすう名乗られへんのは
分からんでもない
I understand why
you're afraid to give in.
せやけど もう時間がないんや
But time's not on our side!
だから おどれに有利な
条件をつけようやないか
So I'll offer you something
to your advantage.
本来やったら 俺のグーに
おどれのチョキは必ず負ける
Technically, my Rock
will beat your Scissors.
しかし それをチャラにしたる
その上
But now, I'm going to
make it even!
On top of that, I'll give you
enough stars to save your life!
星を 生き残れる分の星をやるで！
どや　文句あらんやろ
破格の話や
What are you waiting for?
This is an extraordinary offer!
With this, you'll survive...
これで おどれは生き残る
本望やろ Ｘ？
This is your wish, right, X?!
さあ出てこい 出てこいや Ｘ！
Come on!
Show yourself, X!!
時が流れる　船井の熱弁むなしく
誰も名乗りをあげない
The clock ticked away.
Nobody answered Funai.
Nobody identified himself!
どういうこっちゃ
カードを残したら終わりっちゅう
What is this supposed to mean?
You know the rule. If you still
have cards left, it's over.
ルールを知らんわけでもないやろ
何で名乗り出んのや
What's stopping you now?
船井 いい加減 気がつけよ
Funai, enough of this nonsense.
この限定ジャンケン
その中盤でのアクシデント
Remember the accident
that occurred...
...in the middle of the Restricted
Rock Paper Scissors game?
アクシデント？
異例の措置
Accident?
The exceptional actions...
別室に連れて行かれた
ある男のこと
...taken against the guy
who broke the rules.
何のことや
What are you talking about?
別室へ
連れて行かれたっちゅうことは
Those who had lost their stars
will be taken to the other room.
星を失った奴のことか
でも異例って… 異例…
So what's the exceptional action?
Exceptional...
この男は余分なカードを
トイレに捨て流した
This man flushed his
excess cards down the toilet!
最初に言ったはずだ
We've warned you from the start!
そういう行為は
一切 認めていないと
We will not tolerate such actions!
カードの破棄は 破棄は
He destroyed his cards!
Destroyed!
そうさ　あの時トイレに
破棄されたチョキ３枚は
That's right.
The destroyed cards were not
reflected on the scoreboard.
電光掲示板に
カウントされていねえのさ
つまり Ｘなんていねえんだ
So this means that
there's no X at all!
これでお前は
負けると分かっていても
You'll lose. But then again, you
have no choice but to fight me.
カードを使い切るため
俺と戦うしかねえ
さあ 来な 船井
文字どおり最終戦だ
Hurry, Funai!
This is the final match.
お前は俺と戦い 吐き出す
詐欺と卑劣で蓄えたその星を！
We will fight and
you'll hand them over!
The stars you amassed
by deception and fraud!
何てことや　残り４分
Darn... only 4 minutes left.
あと ひとかきか ふたかきで
手が届くっちゅうのに
I was so close to getting it.
抱きつかれた　溺死寸前の３人に
But 3 men who were going
to drown grabbed him tightly!
クソッ クソッ！
Darn, darn, darn!
時間がねえんだ　ちゃっちゃと
済まそうぜ 星５つの勝負
We don't have time,
let's settle this once and for all!
A 5 star bet.
落ち込むのは その後にしてくれ
Feel free to be
depressed afterwards.
さあ来い 船井　勝負だ
Bring it on, Funai! Let's start!
W-Who are you trying to kid?!
ふざけろ！調子に乗んな
Don't be so arrogant!
Your fate's just the same!
首が絞まっとんのは
お前も同じやろ
やのに主導権を取ったような口で
星５つの勝負や？
You want a 5 star bet?! Quit acting
like you have the upper hand!
無茶もたいがいにせえ アホか
Know your limits, you idiot!
いいとこ３つやろ
それで８個になる
3 stars are sufficient.
You'll have eight then.
あと１つは有り金はたいて買え
Use your money to buy the last
one! You'll survive anyway!
それで生き残れる　やのに
それ以上望むやなんて言語道断
You're being plain greedy
to bargain for more!
強欲も甚だしい
３つ　３つや カイジ
That's my final word!
3 stars... 3 stars, Kaiji!
寝ぼけるなよ 船井　５つだ
それ以外 一切 受け付けない
Wake up, Funai.
It's 5 stars.
I won't accept anything less.
Kaiji...
カイジ
当然の話さ
It's only natural.
100パーセント勝てる勝負に
限界まで はるのは当たり前
If you know you're winning, you'll
put everything on the line too.
状況考えろ　もたもたしとって
時間切れになったら
Look at the situation!
We don't have much time
and if you drag things,
目も当てられへんやろ
だから今は手打ち
everything will be over!
We have to compromise!
譲り合うんや
ざれ言も休み休み言えよ クズ野郎
Cut the nonsense, you scum!
俺たちは ここまで徹底的に
奪い合ってきたんじゃねえか
Didn't we risk everything
to come this far?!
それを言うに事欠いて譲り合い？
ぬかすな　恥を知れ！
So what's up with all
these compromising?!
Stop all this!
Where's your pride?!
悪党なら最後まで悪党でいろよ
If you're a scoundrel,
then act like one till the end!
いいんか？そこの２人
Y-You two are okay with that?!
カイジに成り行きを任せとったら
このまま時間切れ
If you leave things up to Kaiji,
you're wasting your time!
全員 別室行きやぞ
安心しろ
いざとなったら俺の星と
Relax.
At the very least,
you can take my stars...
600万で星６個には到達する
...to get six stars
along with the 6 million.
お前らは それであがればいい
でも それじゃ…
You can use it to get out of this.
But then...
カイジさんは？
その場合…
What about you?
I'll take him down with me.
俺はこのクズと心中する
つ 強がんなや
強がりじゃないさ
S-Stop fooling around!
Who says that I am?!
お前から５つ星を取ろうと
If I don't get your 5 stars,
取れずにこのまま
沈むことになろうと
I'll still sink.
どっちに転んでも同じことなんだ
So either way, it's the same.
同じこと？
It's the same?
同じこと？何や どういうことや
Why? What's his point?
あと３分 あと３分や
こんな時に何を謎めいたことを
3 minutes left... Only 3 minutes.
Why is he acting so
mysterious at this time?
こいつら あと３分で
カードを消耗しきれんのか
Are they planning to get rid of
their cards in 3 minutes?
奴らが持ってるカードは
66枚やから
They have 66 cards
between them...
66枚？え…
66 cards...?
そうだ　俺たちのカードは66枚
お前と１戦すると65枚
That's right. We have 66 cards.
After this match,
we will have 65 cards.
仲間内で消耗しようとしても
必ず１枚残る
Even if they want to play among
themselves, there'll be 1 card left.
３枚破棄というアクシデントが
Due to the accident,
the number of cards...
本来 割り切れるはずの
カードの数を割り切れなくした
...that was supposed to be
divisible is now indivisible.
つまり カイジ 古畑
安藤の中から必ず１人は落ちる
This means one of
the 3 guys will surely fall.
カイジさん
安心しろ
- Kaiji...!
Relax, I'll fall.
俺が落ちる
俺が船井を抱いて落ちる
And I'm bringing Funai along!
カ カイジ…
K-Kaiji!
ムダや　死を負うと決した者に
どんな説得もムダ…
It's no good. When someone
is determined to die,
there's no persuading him!
船井は屈服　屈服せざるをえない
Funai gives up.
He has no choice
but to surrender.
カイジの条件を飲み 星５つの勝負
He accepted Kaiji's conditions.
チェック　セット
Check.
Set.
オープン
Open!
当然 残るカードが
グーと知られている船井は
Funai loses since his remaining
card was already revealed.
敗北　星５つを吐き出す
He hands over the 5 stars.
やったー！カイジさん
- We did it!
- Kaiji!
カイジらは得た
土壇場で星を５つ
Kaiji and gang managed
to win the 5 stars!
残り１分半　幕切れ寸前で
They've finally obtained 9 stars!
ついに至った星９個
They have 1 and a half minutes left
before the curtain closes.
いや 正確には星10個
Technically, they have 10 stars.
これで終えることができれば
まさに快挙
If they can end it here,
it will be a great accomplishment.
だがカイジらが
残したカードは奇数
However, they have 65 cards left.
１人は落ちざるをえない
Someone has to fall.
カイジさん
安心しろ
Kaiji...
Relax...
俺が落ちる
I will fall.
だが ただ落ちるわけじゃない
俺はお前らに託して落ちるんだ
However, it's not that easy.
I'll entrust you with everything
before going down.
託す？
そうだ　聞け
Entrust?
That's right.
Listen up.
俺は復活する
I shall be restored back!
俺はお前らに
星を全部 預けて落ちる
I will give you all the stars now.
Then, during the buy-sell period,
use them to get me out.
お前らは この後の売買タイムの時
その星を使って 俺をあそこから
引き上げてくれればいい
K-Kaiji...
カイジさん 可能なんですか
そんなこと
Is it possible?
I think the organisers will
allow that to happen.
あいつらが星の売買で
救済されるっていうのは
船側も認めてると思うんですけど
But I'm unsure if it includes those
who've been sent to the other room.
それが別室に落ちた人間にまで
及ぶんでしょうか？
Don't worry.
大丈夫　及ぶ　及ぶはずだ
It can be done, I'm sure of it.
でも もしそうじゃなかったら？
売買は前回までで
But... what if that's
not the case?
What if the previous buy-sell
period was the last one?
今回からは
ナシなんてことになったら？
Furuhata, we have no choice.
古畑 他に手はねえのさ
カイジさん
Kaiji...
そのあたりの怪しさは
俺も重々 分かっちゃいるが
I know that it's unsafe to
bet on something so dubious.
Regardless of the reason,
it's our only choice.
紙細工のような利でも
もう これに乗るしかねえんだ
Kaiji...
カイジさん
受け取れ　安藤 古畑
Here. Furuhata, Ando,
I'm depending on you.
頼んだぞ
もちろんっすよ！
Of course!
Y-You can count on us, Kaiji!
任せてください カイジさん
必ず 必ず助けます
We will surely save you!
Here.
ほら　最後の勝負だ
This is the last match.
Use this to defeat me,
お前はそのチョキで俺に勝ち
この胸の星を受け取るんだ
and take this star.
そして俺は垂れ尾のカードと共に
いったん破滅する
I'll take the extra cards
with me,
and dispose them all at once!
Kaiji...
カイジさん…
Check...
チェック　セット　オープン
Set... Open.
カイジはゲーム終了後の星売買に
生き残りを懸ける
Kaiji places his hopes
on the buy-sell period.
自らの命運を古畑と安藤に託した
As such, he places his life in
Furuhata and Ando's hands!
That's the end of the Restricted
Rock Paper Scissors game.
そして限定ジャンケンが終わった
しばらく待機　その場を動くな
Wait, don't move from
this place.
さあ
Move.
Kaiji.
カイジさん
Kaiji... thank you!
Thank you so much!
カイジさん　ありがとう
ありがとうございます
必ず 必ず救い出しますから
We will definitely...
save you later!
Come.
カイジは感じた　古畑と安藤が
とても遠くにいるような違和感
Kaiji felt something then.
He sensed that Furuhata
and Ando were very far away.
俺はもしかしたら
何かとんでもない間違いを…
Did I just make
an incredible mistake?
Take them off.
脱げ　着ているものを脱ぐんだ
すべて
Take off everything,
all of them!
おい 何だよ おい
What's happening?
They are the people
who were ruined...
破滅　破綻者の巣
Hey kid, come here.
来なよ　そこの
あんた 助かる見込みが
あるんだろ
You're waiting to be saved, right?
来な　ここが特等席
救われる者の席
Come here.
These are VIP seats,
for those who will be rescued.
So you will definitely
get out of here?
救われるって何か確信でも？
Of course.
当たり前だ　でなきゃ誰が
こんな損な役回りするか
Otherwise, who would take up
such a thankless role?
Frankly, I had no choice
but to take this role...
もっとも俺はシャバでの
借金がでかすぎるんで
この役回りも仕方ないって言えば
仕方ないんだけどな
...because I was too
deep in debt.
It's tunnelling...
透視か
｢透視｣　この部屋とフロアが
Tunneling... Those who've
been here would know.
There's a one-way magic mirror
between this room and the floor.
マジックミラーで
仕切られてると知るリピーターが
One of their comrades
is sent here...
仲間を１人送り込み
対戦相手のカードを盗み見させる
...to peek at their
opponents' cards.
The number of knocks is a code
to notify their comrades.
あとはミラーを打つ回数などで
仲間に教えればいい
Two groups used this method
and they both succeeded.
今回 この手を使った者は
２組あり 共に成功した
One of the groups was Okabayashi
and his comrades.
１組はこの岡林とその仲間たち
And the other group would be...
そしてもう１組は
A man named Sakai
persuaded Ishida...
サカイという男に説得され
この戦略を受け入れた石田である
...into adopting this strategy.
Oh... You're the kid who
borrowed 10 million, right?
１千万 借りてた子だね
確か カイジ君…
You're Kaiji, right?
Ah, yes...
はい
あんたも助けてもらえる約束で
You're here because they
promised you'll be free, right?
落ちた口かい？
まあ…
Yeah...
そりゃ よかったなあ
でも
Well, good for you.
But still... I don't know if
being here is a good thing.
この状態をよかったと
言うべきかどうか
我々はここを
出ることができるんだよ
Don't worry.
We won't be here long.
Once we're free,
our debts will be cancelled.
出さえすれば借金が帳消し
やり直すことができる
We can start afresh.
もう取り立てに
苦しむことはないんだ
Never again will the
loansharks torment us!
カイジ君 我々はやり直せるんだ
Kaiji... we'll start afresh!
We can start all over again!
やり直せるんだよ
Yeah...
All thanks to Sakai!
これもサカイさんのおかげだ
あの人が俺に
生き残りの道を指してくれたから
He showed me how to survive.
He promised to get six stars,
星を６つ稼いで
俺を引き上げてくれるって
and use them to get me out.
まだ分からないって
That's still uncertain.
まだ船側にお膳を
ひっくり返される可能性がある
The organisers might
just surprise us all.
今回に限り売買はない
For instance, maybe there
will be no buy-sell...
なんてこと
そんなこと
No, no way...
Tonegawa...
利根川
４時間が経過し
4 hours have passed,
the Restricted Rock Paper Scissors
game has ended.
限定ジャンケン そのすべてが終了
However, the floor is still
full of people with 1 or 2 stars.
だが見たところ
星１つ ２つの者たちが
このフロアにあふれている
We won't send all of you
to the other room.
その者たちを
全員別室へ送るというのは
あまりに忍びない
何とか数名でも救いたい 何とか
If possible, we'd like to save
at least a few of you.
そこで検討を重ねた結果
So, we've come to
a conclusion.
特例として星売買の機会を
急きょ設けることにした
You can buy and sell
the stars as a special exception.
売買で星３つになれば救済する
You will need to get
3 stars in order to be saved.
よし　助かる
Yes! I'm saved!
Alright! They can
pick me out with this...
やった！
これで向こうから指名できる
I'll be saved...
助かる！
よかった
Thank goodness...
本当は少し不安だったんだ
Honestly I was afraid.
I feared that I wouldn't
be saved.
ギリギリで
ひっくり返されるんじゃないかと
Now it's all in Sakai's
hands to save me.
あとはサカイさんが
救ってくれるのを待つだけ
何？
- What is it?
- What?
Why are you laughing?
何で笑ってんの あんた
すまん　気に障ったら勘弁な
Sorry if I've offended you.
ただ あまりに
おかしかったもんで
It's just funny.
おかしい？
そのサカイって奴はどこに？
Funny?
Where's that Sakai fellow?
え？どこ… どこって
多分トイレにでも
Where's... Where is he?
Maybe he's in the washroom.
Hey, when will you
realise the truth?
どこまで おめでたいんだ
そのサカイってのは
今 ビールでも飲んでるんだよ
This Sakai is probably
enjoying a beer right now.
上で
う 上？
Up there!
U-Up there?
No, no way!
バカな
最後にお膳をひっくり返すのは
It goes to show that
last minute surprises...
...don't come from
the organisers.
何も船側だけじゃないってことさ
Your buddy had 6 stars, right?
さっきあんた 相棒は
６つ星を稼いだって言ったな
You should have known from the
start that they couldn't save you.
そもそも それじゃ
最初から救われない
That Sakai's been here, isn't it?
サカイってのは
リピーターなんだろ？
Repeaters like him need 4 stars.
リピーターが生き残るには
星は４つ必要なんだ
4 stars?
４つ…
奴がこいつを救おうと思ったら
If Sakai wanted to save him,
he needs to cough up his
own money to buy another star.
自腹を切って もう１つ星を
仕入れなきゃならんってこと
Who would want to do that?
この船で誰がそんなことするかい
It's natural to be betrayed.
裏切られるのが当たり前
ま 仮にそのサカイってのが
Even if Sakai has 7 or 8 stars,
星を７つ ８つ稼いでいたとしても
切られることに変わりはない
he would still betray him.
奴から見たら
こいつは ただの捨て駒
In his eyes,
that guy is only a pawn.
よせ　いい加減にしろ
Stop it, that's enough!
It's true that it's partly
his fault...
それは
あのサカイって奴の言いなりで
本当の人間関係を築かなかった
このおっさんにも非はあるけど
...to follow Sakai blindly and not
develop a true relationship.
だからって
そういう言い方はやめろ
But stop adding fuel
to the fire, will you?
Calm down. Fine, I'll be quiet.
怒るなよ
やめろと言われりゃやめるさ
死んだ犬を蹴飛ばしても仕方ない
Don't bother with
someone like that.
But I'm concerned about
something.
ただ １つ気になるのは
You mentioned true relationship.
あんた
本当の人間関係って言ったけど
本当のって 何？それ
How do you define... true?
I meant...
何って… 一緒に
We went through the game together,
and I believe that...
この限定ジャンケンを
乗り越えてきて その…
We've passed the stage of
betraying or being betrayed.
裏切るとか裏切らないとか
そういうことを超えた
There's trust and then
there's the bond...
信頼っていうか絆…
何それ
What nonsense!
死ぬな お前
You'll die.
What?
If you want to be saved,
ここから
引き上げてもらおうと思ったら
you must have money
like me,
俺みたいにカネを抱いて落ちるか
or have some treasure hidden
in the corrupt world outside.
シャバに強力な
お宝でも隠していて
It's the only passport
to being saved.
助けざるをえないという
状況しかない
Despite that, you're talking
about meaningless things...
なのに お前ときたら
絆とか信頼とか
訳の分からない寝ぼけたことを
...such as bonds and trust...
Shut up, shut up, shut up!
黙れ 黙れ 黙れ！
You don't know how far Furuhata,
Ando and I have gone through!
お前は何も知らないんだ
俺と古畑と安藤がくぐってきた
ここまでの地獄を
絆を 信頼を
Our bond, our trust!
Well, everyone.
さて諸君　時間は10分
You have 10 minutes.
Whoever fails to get 3 stars by
the end of 10 minutes...
この10分で
星３つに至らぬ場合は
今度こそ別室へ行ってもらう
あ あの…
...will be sent to the other room.
Hey!
I want to save someone from
the other room with 3 stars.
星３つで別室の人を
復活させたいんですけど
どうぞご自由に
ありがとうございます
Please go ahead.
Thank you so much!
見たか　聞いたか
Did you see that?
Did you hear that?
They showed no sign of betrayal!
奴らには裏切ろうなんて気は
かけらもねえんだよ
I see. What an
unexpected development.
なるほど　こりゃ予想外の展開だ
Remember, anything can happen.
しかし まだ分からない
まだ言うか
You're still not giving up?
では これより10分　始め
Very well then. Your 10
minutes starts... now!
Sell it to me!
500万 500万！
Sell it to me! Sell it to me!
売ってくれよ
500万だ 500万！
Sell it to me please!
5 million, 5 million!
A-Ando, let's sell one!
Even if we sold one,
安藤 １つ売るぞ
１つ売っても３つは余る
we have 3 left.
We can still save Kaiji!
カイジさんは救える
ほら！500万の奴！
Here's for 5 million!
Yeah, I did it!
やった！やったぞ
これで上に上がれる
I can go up now!
売ってくれよ
散れ！もうねえよ！
- Me too! Me too!
- Go away! We have no more!
残る３つは大切な仲間を
助けるための星だ
We need the last 3
to save someone!
We have no more left!
他をあたんな
離れろ　離れろよ！
Get lost... get lost!
行けったら おい 行け！
Get lost, get lost!
Excuse me...
あの 向こうの人
救いたいんですけど
I want to save someone there.
Furuhata...
古畑
The bond between comrades
that has passed through death.
死をくぐり抜けた仲間の絆
カイジ ついに生還
Finally, Kaiji is saved.
It's him. This man.
この人です　この人 助け…
言ったろ！売る星はもうねえって
There are no more
stars left for sale!
What's wrong, Ando?
どうした 安藤
We can't.
ダメだ　この星もカネも
手放さない
I won't let go of either
the stars or the money.
放したくない
何 言ってんだよ
I don't want to let go...
What? What are you saying?
We wouldn't be able
to save Kaiji then!
それじゃカイジさんが
救えないじゃないか
It doesn't matter!
構わない
あ あ あ あ 安藤！
A-Ando!
At the very end,
due to the betrayal of Ando,
最後の最後　命を託した仲間
安藤の裏切り
the comrade to whom
he entrusted his life,
Kaiji regrets!
カイジ 痛恨！
Next, Resurrection.
次回 ｢回生｣